everyone that will welcome to my channel
in today's video we are doing very easy
everyday and makeup tutorial which is
for beginners so I'll be very
step-by-step talking through this
tutorial for you this is just like the
basics of the basic and just helping if
you've never done makeup before to
understand the steps to do to achieve
this in literally 5 to 10 minutes like
it's the easiest makeup look ever and it
is so effective and I will be very
in-depth talking about the brushes that
we use the products that we use and just
to help you if you are new to makeup
know exactly what to get for your first
makeup kit as well as little tips and
tricks that I've learned along the way
to share with you so I hope you guys
enjoy this tutorial
I really appreciate if you could
subscribe to my channel if you're not
already subscribed I'd love to have you
on board and without further ado let's
jump into it so I'm just going to show
you absolutely everything from the very
start and the first thing that you want
to do is make sure that you have a clean
face so make sure that you have washed
your face and cleanse your face before
applying makeup because you don't want
to be putting makeup over dirty skin you
can either moisturize prime or both and
this is the one that I love to use this
is the Smashbox primer Iser because it
is a moisturizer and a primer in the one
products it says her from leading to
another reason you want to have fresh
skin prime skin before putting on makeup
is you want to have a nice base for the
makeup to sit on so essentially it's
like when you paint a wall he will
always prime it first it's the same for
your face as a same for painting a
picture you always want to make sure
that the face underneath is smooth so
you'll get the best possible results and
it is very very very important to invest
in a good primer but I do find that if
you do not have a primary or self just
moisturizing your skin is a good step to
it my mirror is just over here right now
it's just I've got a new mirror so it's
a little bit I'm just trying to work out
like the angling and stuff all I'm gonna
do is just give this a shake beforehand
and then I'm just gonna pop one pump my
skin and just rub it over so now my skin
is primed you can see it's a little bit
glowy it's got a little bit more
hydration so you can see with my skin I
actually do have quite a bit of acne
I've got some chilling up here at the
moment as well I don't really understand
why
at the moment but it's not behaving very
well so I like to use a full coverage
foundation right now just because it
makes me feel a little bit more
confident when everything is covered so
it's totally up to you you could have a
more natural
what kind of like full and crazy like
I'm gonna do but just as a comparison if
I was having more of a natural skin day
I would use something like a CC cream
this just basically makes it look you
have nice skin so it doesn't cover
everything but it kind of evens out
everything and it's very natural it's
really good like work in school because
people can't tell you your own makeup I
just think you have amazing skin for me
I'm going to use a foundation this one
is one of my favorites it is the NARS
natural radiant long wear foundation and
what it does come true picking your
foundation your CC cream your baby cream
whatever you want to pick always always
when you're in the store match it to
your neck not your hand because I work
fake tan obviously so if I were to match
it to my hand then I have a white face
and a brown neck and it just very weird
so I like to match things to my neck so
make sure to get to color match on a
straw because you do not want to have
the line of death you have really like
foundation in a dark neck or vice versa
and now when it comes to actually
applying the foundation again there's a
lots of different ways to do this for me
personally I love to use a Beauty
Blender it is a little sponge like this
that you put under the top and you
squeeze and all I should get a bit
bigger and I find for me this actually
is the best way to apply foundation or
liquid products and you'll see that when
I put on my face I just bounce it onto
my skin like that I don't drag I bounce
it in and I just feel like it gives the
best kind of finish looks very skin-like
you can use a brush if you prefer that's
completely fine I use either or
depending on what I'm doing and what I
feel like you do always want to make
sure that you're starting from the
middle of your face and then working to
the outside instead of the outside then
inwards it's just so much better to do
it that way I personally like to
actually like put the foundation on my
face like that some people throw it on
the back of the hand some people put it
on like a tray or something I don't
understand that personally because I
find it wastes a lot of product so I
just slap it straight on my skin
and then as you can see with this beauty
blender i am just bouncing it into my
skin and then buffing it and i just want
to make sure that everything is blended
so i'm gonna get all the little corners
like go to my eye in my nose everything
and make sure that it's covering the
whole face so as you can see the
foundation is now on and at this point i
like to grab a little bit of concealer
this is the Rimmel wake me up concealer
which I named right now because I know
they got any sleep last night it was one
of those nights I was tossing and
turning and I was just like oh so I need
this right now
so when it comes to concealer you
probably see on YouTube or Instagram
whatever you know literally like
consider everywhere all over the face
for me personally I don't really contour
that much so what I like to do is grab a
concealer which is about a shade or two
shades lighter than my foundation this
was actually quite a bit lighter and I
will just almost in the form of a
triangle so go across my eye down my
nose and then kind of have that triangle
there I'll just apply that under my eyes
so I'm gonna use that B tab under once
again and I'm just gonna go to the
corner of my eye and then back in and
then down and then kind of blend this
within the triangle that it is you can't
really see where it starts or it
finishes and that is the number one rule
of makeup you do not want to see lines
everything needs to be blended needs to
look natural so the reason why I do that
is I find concealer underneath my eyes
makes a lot of difference in terms of
making me look really awake but as you
can see I am looking quite shiny right
now so as soon as I put on some
concealer I will grab a loose powder now
you can use any kind of powder you want
and you pretty much achieve the same
effect with a loose powder or a pressed
powder like this so this was just from
higher markets full pound that's super
cheap and with this kind of powder I
would just grab it onto a brush and not
a Beauty Blender I would just tap that
underneath my eyes so that is one option
but for me what I like to do is I grab a
loose powder this is the Too Faced peach
perfect powder you don't have to do this
this is just what I do and I've done
lots of things over time but I fund this
gives me the best effect so as you can
see with a loose powder could just tap
the smallest amount into the tray going
my Beach blender again it's still a
little bit wet and I could pick up that
powder and then go over where we put
that concealer and I find that this
gives me the best coverage if I was
having a really really really busy day
where I knew I was wearing makeup for
the whole day I would just grab some
more powder maybe you know put it on my
forehead but for this it's just this is
what I do if I'm just wearing makeup for
a few hours I like to save this much
makeup product as I can I don't like the
ISIL with it so I don't need just put
the powder in the areas I feel I'm gonna
look really shiny and need it so that's
all I would do for like my foundation
and my concealer and then after this
step I will do my eyebrows again if you
have fantastic eyebrows I'm so jealous
if you mine are a little bit sparse
towards the end so I just personally
like to fill them in myself so I know
I'm not everyone out there will need to
fill my eyebrows and I'm very jealous of
you I'll quickly quickly show you this
section just for those that do need it
now when it comes to eyebrows there's
only three different products that you
can all kind of achieve things accent
effect with the first one is the one
that I normally use which I probably
will not use this video because it is a
little bit difficult it does take some
practice this is a dip brow pomade now
it looks very like bizarre gross and
just dirty but essentially I grabbed an
eyebrow brush which looks like this it's
just a very flat brush with a spoolie on
the end which is what you used to brush
your eyebrows into place and I will just
dip that in here and then I will just
almost draw my eyebrow on now
but I suppose if you are a first time
it's a little bit difficult and there's
other options such as powders my
favorite powder is the sleek brow kit I
just think it's the dark bracket well I
started with actually was an eyebrow
pencil so you just use this to obviously
go along and draw on the eyebrow now if
you don't have quite full eyebrows and
you don't really need much except maybe
but a potential then I would definitely
recommend something like the benefit
gimme brow just a little
brush like that which adds some duck
fibers to your brows you're not like
drawing your eyebrow on but you are
adding a little bit of darkness and
depth and just tinting it temporarily so
it looks dark and nice so I'm gonna use
this powder here from the sleek makeup a
brow kit I'm gonna be using an eyebrow
brush with this too so I will actually
zoom you in because it'll be a lot
easier for you to see what I'm doing now
you can see my eye nice and close so
what I like to do is with my eyebrow
brush I will follow the natural shape of
my brows just like that and then I won't
go like too far over how it is and you
can already see it starting to like take
the shape really well and I do have an
eyebrow routine which is more in-depth
that will be in a card on the screen if
you like to click on that and then come
back to this video but for this I'm just
going to show you very quickly start
with a very small amount with a light
hand and then add as I go so browsing
out on and what I like to shoot at this
point in time is grab a brow gel this is
just something which will keep my brows
into place because there's nothing wants
to make one eyebrow hair being up and
down and all over the place and it's
just a bit like can you not so this just
makes it so that my hairs won't move
because I find that if my hairs are like
up down everywhere it's very obvious
than my eyebrows are filled in I like to
bronze at this point and I find that
bronzing makes such a difference when it
comes to bronzes you want to make sure
you don't pick anything which is a
little bit too dark I'm using the park
app princess by Tarte cosmetics as you
can see it's very similar to my neck
shade and I will just grab a brush this
one is just a Sephora Pro airbrush 55
brush I find this works really well for
my cheeks I don't do any sharp
contouring or anything like that I find
that a little bit unnecessary for me so
what I will do is I will put my brush in
the bronzer and I will tap off the
excess because we do not want to have
streaky cheeks and again use a very
light hand do not like small show on to
face start from where like your
sideburns
eventually so I'm gonna start all the
way back here and then I'm going to very
lightly just do some stroke so start up
with my eye ends here down this is kind
of the area I want to stop I don't want
to drag it all the way down here so just
very like hand I'm just adding as I go
and then once most of the product it has
come off my brush I will then very
lightly drag it up to my temples and
then just above my eyebrow now I like to
do this because I feel naturally if you
have quite a bronzed face it would go
kind of from here to here it wouldn't
just be in one strike here it just looks
nice and glowy and natural and not too
scary whereas on this side it looks very
different it's very flat there's no
structure or anything like that so this
is why everyone's and also makes your
face look slimmer this side just looks
really boring okay so I'm feeling nice
and bronzy and glowy which is exactly
what I want and I find this makes your
skin just look really healthy and just
give you that nice like healthy glow
how many times gonna say the same word I
don't at this point I'll add some
mascara now it's a little bit
overwhelming shopping for mascara
because it seems like there's 5 million
different types and they're really it's
probability different times you've just
got to try and see what works for you
there's some with like really really
really big fat ones like this is the
toothpaste better than sex mascara and
that is quite a big fat one and then you
can have other ones which a lot smaller
like that and to anyone else who's never
done makeup with we make like they look
the same to me but there's a difference
just me now I would say for a beginner
my top two mascara is it should be was
so so so good for you number one would
be the dropping on the water this would
be the it cosmetics superhero mascara
this one is nice and thin super easy to
use and looks fantastic I'm just going
to pick up the other one for one second
okay and the other one is the benefit
roller lash now this is a little bit
pricey for a first mascara but you will
it will literally last you so long I've
had the same tube for years and
uses a lot so definitely recommend this
however if you go to Sephora or anything
like that they pretty much always have
the mini version of the roller lash
which is the triple size one I actually
find this is just as good I'm gonna use
the roller lash today on my lashes and I
will zoom you in and I'll show you so it
does come to mascara there is a certain
way to apply it which will give you the
best possible outcome I've noticed and a
purse like my Nana my mum they would
just use their mascara like this where
they just go like that
constantly now that would take a long
time for any product to transfer in my
opinion what I do is I blink onto the
mascara wand so I'll pop it in my eye
here and then I'll blink down and that
covers as much of my lash as possible
and you can see just from that how much
weight on my eye another really good tip
to get right in there is to wiggle
upwards as you go so if you blink wiggle
the brush and then go up it will give it
really really up high lash effect and
then I will just again make sure that
all my lashes are coated just like that
and it's totally your choice if you want
to do your bottom lashes as well I
normally do only the very outside and I
just really really really lightly do it
just like that the next part is
something that I love doing once I
started doing it I couldn't stop because
it just gives you a skin the healthy
sclera and just looks fantastic and that
is to highlight now we're gonna do is
very lightly so we're not gonna go like
super overboard or anything like that
I'm just gonna grab a highlighter this
is by a brand called Al Gore since it's
called the euphoric strobe light you can
use any highlight that you like I'm just
gonna grab a little brush like this what
I'm gonna do is just cut my brush in it
and then tap off the excess and then you
want to feel the highest point of your
cheekbone and you can see naturally I
already have a little bit of a
here so that's where I'm gonna focus the
highlight one so I'm going to be super
super super light with my hand and I'm
just gonna add a little bit of this
strobe light onto my cheekbone you can
see just gives that really really really
healthy glow and I'm not gonna drag it
all the way up and down I'm literally
just dabbing it here and that's it so
again over here just top of my cheekbone
just adding a little bit more as I go
then with any excess that's on my brush
I'll just pop a little bit on my Cupid's
bow there and then just down my nose
this gives the illusion that my nose is
straight so just add a little bit down
there and then finally tiny bit
underneath my eyebrows so as we're
keeping it quite natural we're gonna
keep the lips quite natural - you can do
anything on just a lip liner and some
vaseline or some lip gloss lip balm
whatever I'm just gonna grab a lip liner
which is the same color as my lip and
not to over draw too much but just add
some nice shape I'm just gonna fill in
the shape of my lips so lip sticks
basically come down to stuff like this
so you can have a liquid lipstick which
looks like that and you just pop it on
your lips I find for me personally I
always use liquid lipsticks they last
through eating and drinking and
everything and last the longest they can
feel a little bit dry and uncomfortable
the beginning but make sure that you get
on with a really good formula and then
you won't have that and it's normally
kiss proof just putting that in there in
case you need to know that there's
nothing worse than we're gonna lip
sticking and kissing someone and it's on
them it's off you and it's all just a
little bit embarrassing so however I
kind of feel like as a beginner I would
prefer to use a lipstick this one's my
Mac it's velvet teddy
it's like my favorite favorite favorite
lip soup for time I used to wear it all
the time when I started to wear makeup
so we're going to pop this on our lips
again just following the shape of where
the lip liner
[Music]
and that is our makeup completes if I
wasn't talking through this this would
only take you about five to ten minutes
it wouldn't take that long at all this
is the kind of makeup that I would say
is that your features but enhanced I
love this if I'm just feeling a little
bit rubbish and then I have a face like
this I feel ten times better you can see
all my acne pimples are hidden
my skin just looks Chloe I look healthy
I look like I've just come back from
holiday so I love this kind of makeup
look and I also love it there's no I
shot or anything because it's just so
wearable for everything so I hope that
you enjoyed and appreciated is kind of
like talk-through step step step step
step tutorial because this is definitely
something that I had like my dad in mind
I was like how would he I like spoke to
him about makeup what would he want to
know um so I hope that this helped you
if it did help you please let me know
because I would love to hear that
and I'll see you guys in my next video
so until then bye